<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Synthesis Coding</title>
    <link>https://synthesiscoding.com</link>
    <description>Articles on Synthesis Coding methodology for AI-assisted professional software development.</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 07:36:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://synthesiscoding.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>

    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Why Synthesis Coding Still Writes Code in the Age of LLMs]]></title>
      <link>https://synthesiscoding.com/articles/why-synthesis-coding-still-writes-code-in-the-age-of-llms/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://synthesiscoding.com/articles/why-synthesis-coding-still-writes-code-in-the-age-of-llms/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>The answer is not "just let the model do it" — and code matters more, not less, as AI gets dramatically better Last spring, my son Fitz and I had an afternoon math duel. He was twelve at the time. Sharp. Competitive. He took on the puzzle the traditional way — paper, pencil, and focused [...]</description>
      <category>Philosophical foundation</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Vibe Coding and Synthesis Coding: Two Complementary Approaches]]></title>
      <link>https://synthesiscoding.com/articles/vibe-coding-and-synthesis-coding-two-approaches-one-developer/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://synthesiscoding.com/articles/vibe-coding-and-synthesis-coding-two-approaches-one-developer/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>Why the conversation isn't about which approach is better — it's about knowing when to use each This blog post is for software engineers, engineering leaders, and anyone interested in AI-assisted development. Since publishing my series on Synthesis Coding, I've received a recurring question: "How do</description>
      <category>Comparison and guidance</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Polyrepo Synthesis: Synthesis Coding Across Multiple Repositories with Claude Code in Visual Studio Code]]></title>
      <link>https://synthesiscoding.com/articles/polyrepo-synthesis-synthesis-coding-across-multiple-repositories-with-claude-code-in-visual-studio-code/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://synthesiscoding.com/articles/polyrepo-synthesis-synthesis-coding-across-multiple-repositories-with-claude-code-in-visual-studio-code/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>I wrote this blog post for Software Engineers, Architects, and Technical Leads. It is code-heavy and implementation-focused. This weekend I was working across three repositories simultaneously in Visual Studio Code. I worked on RagBot — a multi-LLM chatbot that lets you switch between OpenAI, Anthro</description>
      <category>Advanced patterns</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Seventeen years ago, I built a tool for the open Web. This weekend, I modernized it using Synthesis Coding with Claude Code AI]]></title>
      <link>https://synthesiscoding.com/articles/seventeen-years-ago-i-built-a-tool-for-the-open-web-this-weekend-i-modernized-it-using-synthesis-coding-with-claude-code-ai/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://synthesiscoding.com/articles/seventeen-years-ago-i-built-a-tool-for-the-open-web-this-weekend-i-modernized-it-using-synthesis-coding-with-claude-code-ai/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>In 2008, I released a WordPress plugin called Blogroll Links. The plugin displayed lists of links on WordPress pages using a shortcode. But the idea behind it was more ambitious than the implementation might suggest. I built Blogroll Links because I believed people should control their own online pr</description>
      <category>Case study</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Synthesis Engineering: The Professional Practice Emerging in AI-Assisted Development]]></title>
      <link>https://synthesiscoding.com/articles/synthesis-engineering-the-professional-practice-emerging-in-ai-assisted-development/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://synthesiscoding.com/articles/synthesis-engineering-the-professional-practice-emerging-in-ai-assisted-development/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>Why the most effective engineering organizations are developing systematic approaches that go beyond vibe coding — and why this practice needs a name This blog post is for CTOs, Engineering Leaders, Technical Executives. I've also written it be accessible to non-technical readers. I've had the same </description>
      <category>Foundation</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Synthesis Coding with Claude Code: Technical Implementation and Workflows]]></title>
      <link>https://synthesiscoding.com/articles/synthesis-engineering-with-claude-code-technical-implementation-and-workflows/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://synthesiscoding.com/articles/synthesis-engineering-with-claude-code-technical-implementation-and-workflows/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>A hands-on guide to practicing Synthesis Coding (a.k.a. Synthesis Engineering) with concrete examples, real workflows, and lessons from production systems I wrote this blog post for Software Engineers, Architects, and Technical Leads. This one is code-heavy and implementation-focused. In the first t</description>
      <category>Technical guide</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[The Synthesis Engineering Framework: How Organizations Build Production Software with AI]]></title>
      <link>https://synthesiscoding.com/articles/the-synthesis-engineering-framework-how-organizations-build-production-software-with-ai/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://synthesiscoding.com/articles/the-synthesis-engineering-framework-how-organizations-build-production-software-with-ai/</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <description>From individual practice to organizational capability: a systematic approach to human-AI collaboration in professional software development This blog post is for Engineering Leaders, CTOs, and Product Managers. In my previous article, I introduced Synthesis Coding (a.k.a. Synthesis Engineering) — th</description>
      <category>Framework</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>